ERIC TJOSSEM

FRONT END DEVELOPER WITH A PASSION FOR BEAUTIFUL DESIGN

tjosse.me erictj@gmail.com (641) 990-9591

Hi, I'm Eric! I love writing responsive and semantic front end code. I'm always keeping an eye on new Javascript libraries as they come out, and I make full use of preprocessors (like Sass and Haml) in my workflow. I have a strong□ preference for small, highly collaborative teams and a development culture that values the user experience.

A web application can't survive on code alone; even as a developer, I find myself building my own mockups for projects and considering interactions carefully from the perspective of the user. I look forward to putting my understanding of event flow, typography, and usability to use in my future roles.

Does this sound like a good fit? Email me at erictj@gmail.com or tweet @etjossem.□

TECH HTML / Haml CSS / Sass JS / Coffee

Ruby (Rails)Python (Django)PHP (CakePHP)jQueryAngular.jsBackbone.jsMySQL / PostgresDeploymentVersioning (Git)

EXPERIENCE

Lead Front End Developer at Chariot • May 2014 to Present

Led a small development team during transition to a federated API. Developed a ticketing and check-in system for Chariot riders. Designed, built, and released a customer-facing mobile app. **Web Stack**: Angular.js, Sass, Haml, Javascript, MySQL. **Mobile Stack**: Hybrid Mobile - Angular.js via Cordova.

Software Developer at Rinse · December 2013 to May 2014

Designed Backbone.js based mobile application in Trigger.io to improve on legacy app. Led rework of main site (www.rinse.com) frontend, under mobile responsive grid system

Created my own mockups for many new features, in collaboration with primary designer.

Web Stack: Django, Sass, Hamlpy, Javascript, PostgreSQL. Mobile Stack: Hybrid Mobile - Backbone.js via Trigger.io.

Software Engineer at ItsOn · August 2013 to November 2013

Built internal tools for the development and quality assurance teams. Created detailed documentation on tools and development processes. Provided constant communication and iteration in an Agile/Scrum environment.

Web Stack: Drupal, PHP, Javascript, MySQL.

Front End Developer at Goodsmiths • May 2012 to July 2013

Built the user interface for bulk editing listings, available to premium customers. Created a reusable template for gift guides (Christmas, Valentine's, Mother's Day, etc.).

Designed the Group Offers page, featuring fully mobile-responsive image tiles. **Web Stack**: Ruby on Rails, Sass, Haml, Javascript, MySQL.

Systems Administrator at KDIC 88.5 FM • January 2009 to May 2012

Designed and built a custom blog for the station (http://kdic.grinnell.edu/). Set up a simulcast server to stream the station's audio content over the web. Developed a custom analytics solution for the streaming server to track listenership by program.

Web Stack: WordPress, PHP, Icecast2, MySQL

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts (Political Science) 2008 to 2012

Grinnell College, Grinnell, IA